SCOTT

SILVER

Software Developer

CONTACT ME!

(615)-974-6679

scottsilver47@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/scottsilver47/

github.com/Scott47

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a learner, a teacher, and advocate with a passion for problem solving and teamwork. Past experience with spatial data research and using student data to inform daily instruction as a teacher fueled my interest in software development.

PROJECTS

XC STATS

FINAL CAPSTONE github.com/Scott47

XC Stats is a full stack Django/React app that allows high school cross country coaches to manage runner, team, and event information. Coaches can build and edit rosters, track runner contact information, meet times, runner pace, personal records on a specific course, etc.

OUR STORY MAPS FRONT-END CAPSTONE

github.com/Scott47

Our Story Maps is a single page application using React.JS and ArcGIS API. It is intended for users to create immersive stories about place combining text, interactive maps ,and other multimedia context. The app demonstrates full CRUD functionality. User data and story elements were stored using JSON-server.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA-BIRMINGHAM (UAB)

B.A. Anthropology

UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA-BIRMINGHAM (UAB)

33 credit hours toward M.A. Anthropology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/ NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

- Hands on application of Object Oriented Programming fundamentals through group and individual projects in a simulated agile, mockcompany environment
- Front-end development using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, third-party APIs, ERDs (Entity Relationship Diagrams) and data relationshipsServer-side development with Python/Django, Django RES Framework, React with Hooks, including SQL
- Source code version control with git/GitHub
- Built a full stack application with Django & React
- Built a single page application with React and ArcGIS API for developers

TEACHER, MATH CONTENT CHAIR

2013 - 2019

- Collected and analyzed student data to plan and execute daily lesson plans.
- Utilized Microsoft Excel, Kickboard, LiveSchool, and Illuminate
 Education software to input, sort, and analyze student data to inform
 daily instruction, develop growth mindsets and create a positive
 learning culture.
- Designed and executed professional development for teachers.Led and facilitated professional learning community of math teachers from 5th through 8th grade
- Served on school leadership team and strategic school design team.

PROGRAM COORDINATOR/FARM TO SCHOOL JONES VALLEY TEACHING FARM

2009 - 2012

- Researched and collected data to successfully advocate for wellness policies for school food improvement in Jefferson County Schools.
- Organized and conducted professional development workshops for teachers and child nutrition workers.
- Developed Good School Food program by investing community stakeholders for future implementation of school gardens, farmer's markets and healthy food education

INTERNSHIP, RESEARCH TEAM LEAD, NASA DEVELOP PROGRAM, UAB

2008 - 2009

 Developed West Nile Virus risk model for Auburn, AL by investigating environmental factors and collected mosquito data using geospatial ArcGIS and processed ASTER and Landsat imagery.

PROGRAM COORDINATOR, UAB-SCHOOL OF PUBLIC HEALTH

2005 - 2008

- Served as liaison between UAB, investigators, NIH Fogarty Fellows, and five foreign sites (Bangladesh, China, India, Pakistan, Ukraine)
- Researched, wrote, and administered NIH grants.
- Co-taught scientific writing workshop at the Tuberculosis Research Centre in Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India
- Taught qualitative methods to investigators at the CDC in Beijing, China